<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jared Monger</title>
    <link>https://www.jmonger.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jared Monger</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 09:05:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.jmonger.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Installing Arch Linux in VMware Workstation Player</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2020/09/installing-arch-linux-in-vmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 09:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2020/09/installing-arch-linux-in-vmware/</guid>
      <description>During this time when we are all isolated in our homes because of COVID-19, I have tried to make the most of it and learn some new skills. Something I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to get better at is Linux. I learn best by diving into the deep end of the pool, so I decided to install Arch Linux in VMware Workstation Player as a learning experience. This blog post is to document the process for future reference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from Wordpress to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2020/01/migrating-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 10:28:28 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2020/01/migrating-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>For around 6 years, I ran a Wordpress site called Numbermonger that focused on accounting and technology. The site averaged a few thousand visitors a month - mostly SAS programmers and other technology-minded accountants. Wordpress had a number of features that I enjoyed using, but I eventually came to the conclusion that it was overkill for my needs. Work and personal life also became busier, and my appetite to sit down and write dried up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts on the Affordable Care Act</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2013/12/some-thoughts-on-the-affordable-care-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 21:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2013/12/some-thoughts-on-the-affordable-care-act/</guid>
      <description>(This post is my opinion only and in no way constitutes the views of my employer or clients. It&amp;rsquo;s also written with an assumption the goal of a healthcare system is to provide quality care at the lowest price possible without disincentivizing providers. If you don&amp;rsquo;t start there, the rest doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter.)&#xA;Price elasticity of demand Let&amp;rsquo;s go back to Economics 101. One of the foundational concepts of that class is price elasticity of demand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can You Teach Ethics?</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/11/can-you-teach-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 20:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/11/can-you-teach-ethics/</guid>
      <description>CPAs across the country are required to sit through various amounts of ethics training every two years. I sat thought mine on Friday. Inevitably during these sessions, the question comes up, &amp;ldquo;Can ethics be taught?&amp;rdquo; My own answer to this question has fluctuated since it was first posed to me as a graduate student. Could more effective ethics training have prevented the major accounting failures of the last 10 years? I am, by nature and temperament, a realist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everybody Stay Calm</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/11/everybody-stay-calm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 14:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/11/everybody-stay-calm/</guid>
      <description>You may have noticed the blog posts have been in short supply since last year. Well, frankly, it&amp;rsquo;s because I&amp;rsquo;ve been a lot busier and the nature of my work has changed significantly. Instead of spending hours debugging code and writing the perfect formula in Excel, I&amp;rsquo;m now delegating responsibilities and managing people. This has been an exciting and different world for me. As far as my plans for this blog, I&amp;rsquo;m still going to post the odd technical tip as projects come up, but I may shift some focus to current accounting news and people management since that&amp;rsquo;s where I am spending my time these days.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stanford International Bank Fraud Conviction: 110 Year Prison Sentence</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/09/stanford-international-bank-fraud-conviction-110-year-prison-sentence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 19:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/09/stanford-international-bank-fraud-conviction-110-year-prison-sentence/</guid>
      <description>Two years ago, I wrote a long post about the Stanford International Bank Fraud.&#xA;I recently thought about the story and realized I never followed up to see what happened. After a quick Google search, I was pleased to see that Allen Stanford was convicted and sentenced to 110 years in prison.&#xA;The most amazing part is even after his conviction Stanford still claims he wasn&amp;rsquo;t running a Ponzi scheme and the government is responsible for his victims&amp;rsquo; losses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excel Pull Function</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/02/excel-pull-function-creating-dynamic-links-to-closed-workbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 21:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/02/excel-pull-function-creating-dynamic-links-to-closed-workbooks/</guid>
      <description>I was working on a project this week that required aggregation of data from many, many different Excel workbooks (and various tabs within those workbooks) into one unified dashboard. Now, this can be accomplished with traditional linking, but anyone who has tried to link more than a few workbooks together will tell you this is a pain to maintain and often not very reliable.&#xA;One useful function for creating dynamic links within the same workbook is INDIRECT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Problem With College</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/10/the-problem-with-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2011 19:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/10/the-problem-with-college/</guid>
      <description>Much of the discussion surrounding the Occupy Wall Street protest movement has turned towards the rising costs of higher education. This is likely because many of the protesters are young, college educated and saddled with enormous federal debt. The Los Angeles Times had a piece this weekend discussing the issue. It was good article, but I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed something missing in all the coverage. Something that colleges, students and even parents don&amp;rsquo;t seem to want to talk about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Tulip Bubble of 1636</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/09/the-tulip-bubble-of-1636/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2011 18:19:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/09/the-tulip-bubble-of-1636/</guid>
      <description>With all the news coverage on the recent &amp;ldquo;Great Recession&amp;rdquo;, you might think bursts of speculation and the subsequent collapse in prices are unique to the modern age. They&amp;rsquo;re not.&#xA;During the latter half of 1636 Tulip prices in Holland skyrocketed. By the peak of the bubble in February 1637, a single tulip bulb was selling for more than the average laborer made in an entire year. There was a strong belief that tulip prices would only continue to rise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Batman Equation</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/08/the-batman-equation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 21:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/08/the-batman-equation/</guid>
      <description>There is a geometric equation going around the internet that supposedly generates the Batman symbol. Best I can tell, it started at this site, and blew up from there. A user at Stack Exchange took it upon himself to test whether it worked. He mapped out the various functions and looks like it does. Pretty cool.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sino-Forest, Short Sellers Allege Ponzi Scheme</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/06/sino-forest-short-sellers-allege-ponzi-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 18:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/06/sino-forest-short-sellers-allege-ponzi-scheme/</guid>
      <description>There is an interesting alleged accounting fraud unfolding in China. Sino-Forest Corporation, a Chinese company in the business of selling timber, has been accused by short sellers of being a massive Ponzi scheme. Like Enron, they seem to be running their business through a complex system of subsidiaries in order to obfuscate transactions. One of the funnier quotes from the short sellers&amp;rsquo; report is below:&#xA;Despite TRE’s opacity on the revenue side, we have overwhelming evidence that the $231.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R for SAS and SPSS Users, A Review</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/06/learning-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 15:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/06/learning-r/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve followed me for any length of time, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that I&amp;rsquo;m a proponent of good data analysis. I was not formally educated as a programmer but I&amp;rsquo;ve found a solid understanding of data manipulation has served me well in my work as an accountant.&#xA;My primary tool for 4 years has been SAS. It is an awesome, easy to learn language that has allowed me to look like a hero on numerous projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin: A Money Launderer&#39;s Dream Come True</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/05/bitcoin-a-money-launderers-dream-come-true/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 17:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/05/bitcoin-a-money-launderers-dream-come-true/</guid>
      <description>I first heard about Bitcoin when Steve Gibson did a podcast on it a few months ago. Essentially, it&amp;rsquo;s a medium of exchange just like any other currency. The major differences are 1. &amp;ldquo;coins&amp;rdquo; are simply bits in the system with no physical reality (actually, most of the US money supply has no physical reality either, but that&amp;rsquo;s a post for another day), 2. transfers can&amp;rsquo;t be traced, and 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ladies and Gentlemen, My Brother</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/04/ladies-and-gentlemen-my-brother/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2011 22:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/04/ladies-and-gentlemen-my-brother/</guid>
      <description>My younger brother (who also happens to be an accounting major), is finishing up his senior year at University of Tennessee. Apparently, his tax teacher told the class they could use one page of notes on their last test. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what the professor was expecting, but this is what my brother brought. Classic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>April Fools Is Better With Visual Basic</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/april-fools-is-better-with-visual-basic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 19:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/april-fools-is-better-with-visual-basic/</guid>
      <description>Happy April Fools-Eve, my fellow practical joke connoisseurs. As someone who enjoys a good laugh at another&amp;rsquo;s expense and also happens to be a bit of a geek, I thought would post the VBA code for two of my favorite Excel-based jokes. For those who aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with Visual Basic for Applications (&amp;ldquo;VBA&amp;rdquo;), it&amp;rsquo;s a programming language that Microsoft created which allows users to customize the functionality of MS Office. For example, I have two macros setup which create hotkeys for Paste Values and Paste Formulas, since I use those on a daily basis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping an MS Access Database to SAS Library</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/mapping-an-ms-access-database-to-sas-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 16:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/mapping-an-ms-access-database-to-sas-library/</guid>
      <description>This post is for people, like myself, who assume things are harder than they usually are. Worked on an analysis yesterday where I needed to map an Access database to a SAS library so I could use the tables in some joins. My first thought was ODBC. I proceeded to setup the connection, only to find out my company didn&amp;rsquo;t give everyone that ability. Bummer. 15 minutes wasted.&#xA;Searched around and couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any other ideas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Dashboard Your Scorecard</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/joa-dashboard-your-scoreboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 14:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/joa-dashboard-your-scoreboard/</guid>
      <description>The Journal of Accountancy had a good article last month on building Excel-based dashboards. It got the creative juices flowing for me, and I am thinking about integrating some dashboards into my daily work. Modern BI tools like SAS and Business Objects can be used to automate feeds to predesigned Excel dashboards which can then be accessed by anyone over a shared network drive. The hardest (and most important) step is determining the appropriate metrics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Anatomy of an Email Storm</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/the-anatomy-of-an-email-storm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 16:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/the-anatomy-of-an-email-storm/</guid>
      <description>The Wall Street Journal devoted a full article this week to the Reply-All button. Towards the end, they brought up one of Reply-All&amp;rsquo;s unintended consequences: the email storm. This is where someone accidentally emails a very large distribution list, people then Reply-All asking to be removed, then the whole thing explodes until IT gets involved.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this happen twice. Both times it unfolded exactly like the chart below. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit, by the time it gets to Phase 4, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to resist the urge to jump into the mix.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bill Gates TED Talk: How State Budgets Are Breaking US Schools</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/bill-gates-ted-talk-how-state-budgets-are-breaking-us-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 14:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/bill-gates-ted-talk-how-state-budgets-are-breaking-us-schools/</guid>
      <description>Bill Gates gave a talk at TED this week that has generated quite a bit of buzz. The video is below. According to Gates, the major issue driving the underfunding of education is state pension obligations. Adding to the mix are governmental accounting standards which allow states to use unrealistic rates of return to discount the liability. Two University of Chicago economists have estimated that if more realistic rates were used the total unfunded pension liability for all US states changes from $310 billion to $2 trillion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compound Interest: A Lesson From My Dad</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/compound-interest-a-lesson-from-my-dad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 21:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/compound-interest-a-lesson-from-my-dad/</guid>
      <description>“The most powerful force in the universe is compound interest” -Albert Einstein&#xA;My dad first taught me about compound interest when I was 18 years old. I was working for him, doing maintenance on our family&amp;rsquo;s office building, and had some extra money burning a hole in my pocket. He wanted to teach me that there are better things to do with money than just blow it on music and video games (a tough argument for a teenager).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s All Good. At Least Until The Robots Learn the Nuclear Launch Codes.</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/ken-jennings-its-all-good-at-least-until-the-robots-learn-the-nuclear-launch-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 16:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/ken-jennings-its-all-good-at-least-until-the-robots-learn-the-nuclear-launch-codes/</guid>
      <description>Slate has an article from Ken Jennings talking about his match this week against IBM&amp;rsquo;s Watson Supercomputer. This was my favorite quote.&#xA;So my defeat at the hands of a machine has a happy ending, after all. At least until the whole system becomes sentient and figures out the nuclear launch codes. But I figure that&amp;rsquo;s years away.&#xA;Pretty soon we&amp;rsquo;ll all need some Old Glory Insurance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Grandfather&#39;s Books</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/my-grandfathers-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 19:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/my-grandfathers-books/</guid>
      <description>Last month, my family and I made a trip to Florida to visit my mom&amp;rsquo;s parents. We had a great visit and while I was there, my grandmother offered to let me have some books from grandfather&amp;rsquo;s study. Grandpa was an engineer turned businessman, and spent his career building things: first automotive parts, then shareholder value.&#xA;He had some great accounting textbooks from his MBA at University of Chicago in the 1960&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excel: VLOOKUP vs. MATCH / INDEX. No Contest.</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/excel-vlookup-vs-match-index-no-contest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 17:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/excel-vlookup-vs-match-index-no-contest/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I posted a tweet declaring that VLOOKUP (the popular joining function in Excel) was for newbs and that cool kids used MATCH and INDEX. I got some interesting responses, so I thought I would take a moment to defend my position and maybe gain some converts.&#xA;VLOOKUP in Action Essentially, both sets of functions are simple ways to join two tables that share a common field. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of VLOOKUP in action.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wired: Cracking the Scratch Lottery Code</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/wired-cracking-the-scratch-lottery-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 14:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/wired-cracking-the-scratch-lottery-code/</guid>
      <description>This was an interesting story from Wired about a Canadian statistician who cracked the Ontario lottery scratch-off algorithm.&#xA;The apparent randomness of the scratch ticket was just a facade, a mathematical lie. And this meant that the lottery system might actually be solvable, just like those mining samples. “At the time, I had no intention of cracking the tickets,” he says. He was just curious about the algorithm that produced the numbers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Lords of Finance, The Bankers Who Broke the World</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/01/book-review-lords-of-finance-the-bankers-who-broke-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 18:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/01/book-review-lords-of-finance-the-bankers-who-broke-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Recently finished a book on the Great Depression called Lords of Finance: The Bankers Who Broke the World. It was a 500+ page behemoth, but a surprisingly quick read. The story focuses on four central bankers during the 20s and 30s: Benjamin Strong of the Federal Reserve of New York, Montagu Norman of the Bank of England, Emile Morceau of the Banque de France, and Hjalmer Schacht of the Reichsbank of Germany.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dickens on Personal Budgeting</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/01/dickens-on-personal-budgeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 14:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/01/dickens-on-personal-budgeting/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Annual income twenty pounds, annual expenditure nineteen six, result happiness. Annual income twenty pounds, annual expenditure twenty pound ought and six, result misery.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Charles Dickens, David Copperfield</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Provisions in the Senate&#39;s Tax Cut Extension Bill</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/joa-provisions-in-the-senates-tax-cut-extension-bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 21:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/joa-provisions-in-the-senates-tax-cut-extension-bill/</guid>
      <description>In case you were curious about the exact provisions in the Senate&amp;rsquo;s tax bill the Journal of Accountancy has a detailed article.&#xA;The bill has provisions from four of the five tax areas that were considered to be important for Congress to address during its current “lame duck” session: the estate tax, expiring tax cuts, expired tax provisions, and an alternative minimum tax (AMT) patch. The bill as introduced does not address the expanded Form 1099 reporting requirements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NYT: Still Digging</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/nyt-still-digging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 17:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/nyt-still-digging/</guid>
      <description>From Thomas Friedman. I love this.&#xA;More than ever, America today reminds me of a working couple where the husband has just lost his job, they have two kids in junior high school, a mortgage and they’re maxed out on their credit cards. On top of it all, they recently agreed to take in their troubled cousin, Kabul, who just can’t get his act together and keeps bouncing from relative to relative.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NYT: Ireland Parliament to Vote on Austere Budget</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/nyt-ireland-parliament-to-vote-on-austere-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 23:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/nyt-ireland-parliament-to-vote-on-austere-budget/</guid>
      <description>Sobering politics these days in Ireland. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure our own government would be capable of passing a budget like this.&#xA;DUBLIN — Pressured by onerous debts and fears of financial contagion, the Irish government introduced one of the strictest budgets in the nation’s history Tuesday, raising taxes and slashing government and welfare spending to qualify for an 85 billion euro aid package from its European partners. &amp;hellip; “This is a bailout for the speculators and the financial markets of the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should Accountants Be Required to Code</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/should-accountants-be-required-to-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 17:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/should-accountants-be-required-to-code/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, I wonder where I fit on the career spectrum. I am trained as a CPA and 90% of my daily work involves accounting in some form. However, I am also a programmer who geeks out when I find a new way to automate processes or transform data into knowledge. My boss made a comment a few weeks ago in a meeting, “If you want to get Jared excited, ask him about two things: 1) His family or 2) SAS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GigaOM: Get Business Intelligence Ready for the Real-Time Web</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/gigaom-get-business-intelligence-ready-for-the-real-time-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 21:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/gigaom-get-business-intelligence-ready-for-the-real-time-web/</guid>
      <description>GigaOM had a good article this morning called Get Business Intelligence Ready for the Real-Time Web. Here&amp;rsquo;s what they say BI 2.0 should look like. Not sure the tools exist yet to accomplish, but I can see things moving in this direction. Well designed dashboards do some of this already.&#xA;The future of BI 2.0 will not rely on server power, but on the human power of the entire organization to capture everything, convert social media into tangible business objects, and automate real-time business processes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FASB/IASB Reaffirm Convergence Timeline</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/fasbiasb-reaffirm-convergence-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 16:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/fasbiasb-reaffirm-convergence-timeline/</guid>
      <description>FASB released a report on November 29 with the unwieldy title &amp;ldquo;Progress Report on Commitment to Convergence of Accounting Standards and a Single Set of High Quality Global Accounting Standards&amp;rdquo;. Bottom line, FASB and IASB have reaffirmed their commitment to convergence. High priority projects are on track for a June 2011 completion date. The projects included in that designation are the following.&#xA;Financial instruments Leases Revenue Recognition Consolidations Fair value measurement Derecognition Insurance Contracts That pretty much covers, well, I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;hellip;80%-90% of everything I&amp;rsquo;ve ever learned about accounting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HBR: Why It&#39;s Better to Be Smart and Wrong than Just Silent</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/hbr-why-its-better-to-be-smart-and-wrong-than-just-silent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 21:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/hbr-why-its-better-to-be-smart-and-wrong-than-just-silent/</guid>
      <description>I received this same advice from a senior auditor in a performance review four years ago. It is some of the best career advice I&amp;rsquo;ve ever received.&#xA;When you&amp;rsquo;re not sure what to do or how to proceed, don&amp;rsquo;t start with a blank slate and ask for help. Instead, start with what you do know, state your intended direction (and rationale behind it) and then get the buy-in or feedback of your manager.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HBR: On Creative Accounting, Two Creativity Myths</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/hbr-on-creative-accounting-two-creativity-myths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 14:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/hbr-on-creative-accounting-two-creativity-myths/</guid>
      <description>Harvard Business Review had a good blog post this morning called On Creative Accounting: Two Creativity Myths. The term &amp;ldquo;creative accounting&amp;rdquo; conjures up images of Enron, and other massive financial reporting frauds. However, the author points out that creativity, itself, is morally neutral, and because creativity in accounting can be bad, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that it must be bad. Also, I liked the cartoon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NBJ: Mortgage rates fall again</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/nbj-mortgage-rates-fall-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 17:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/nbj-mortgage-rates-fall-again/</guid>
      <description>Nashville Business Journal had a story this morning about mortgage interest rates continuing to fall. The 15 year fixed average is barely higher than average annual inflation. It&amp;rsquo;s crazy. If you are in the market for a home, now is the time. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t get any better for buyers than this.&#xA;Long-term mortgage rates fell to new lows this week, after the Federal Reserve’s announcement to step back into the Treasuries market.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>xkcd: SQL Injection Comic</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/xkcd-sql-injection-comic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 13:54:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/xkcd-sql-injection-comic/</guid>
      <description>I love xkcd. This is old, but I&amp;rsquo;m slow on the uptake. I also love that a comic spawned a website on how to prevent SQL injection attacks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAS EG: Filtering a Dataset via Prompt Manager Variable</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/sas-eg-filtering-a-dataset-via-prompt-manager-variable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 15:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/sas-eg-filtering-a-dataset-via-prompt-manager-variable/</guid>
      <description>Nobody who reads this blog is likely a SAS programmer. However, on the off chance this would be useful to someone who finds it via Google, I wanted to post. Currently, I am working on a project in SAS Enterprise Guide where I needed to allow the user to provide variable value(s) via prompt manager and then filter the resulting dataset based on the user&amp;rsquo;s input. After rubbing a few brain cells together, created a macro that does the trick.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NYT: It’s Morning in India</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/nyt-its-morning-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 14:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/nyt-its-morning-in-india/</guid>
      <description>I enjoyed this article. I used to share projects with Deloitte&amp;rsquo;s office in Hyderabad, India. During busy season, I would work on gathering the relevant project components during the day, discuss the requirements on the phone that night, and when I came in the next morning, there in my inbox would sit the completed project. Pretty amazing, really. One gentleman worked over 400 hours during January 2008 to meet my project deadlines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Whose Goodwill Is It?</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/joa-whose-goodwill-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 14:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/joa-whose-goodwill-is-it/</guid>
      <description>This is interesting. Not sure I agree with the ruling. However, my father is a dentist who&amp;rsquo;s owned his practice for 25+ years, so I&amp;rsquo;m a little biased.&#xA;The U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Washington recently held that goodwill created while a dentist was employed by his solely owned corporation belonged to the corporation and not to him. As a result, the dentist was required to characterize as a corporate dividend rather than a long-term capital gain the amount he received for the goodwill from the sale of his practice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Genealogy, Chance, and God</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/thoughts-on-genealogy-chance-and-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 22:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/thoughts-on-genealogy-chance-and-god/</guid>
      <description>Prelude: This post doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much particularly to do with numbers or accounting, but it does have a lot to do with me. There are some thoughts on probability as well.&#xA;Those who follow me on Twitter may have noticed, I have developed a recent fascination with genealogy. It started a few weeks ago during a conversation with my wife where I mentioned it might be nice to pass on a family tree to my son.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taleb on Corporate Bankruptcy</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/taleb-on-corporate-bankruptcy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2010 19:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/taleb-on-corporate-bankruptcy/</guid>
      <description>But corporations can go bust as often as they like, thus subsidizing us consumers by transferring their wealth into our pockets - the more bankruptcies, the better it is for us. Government is a more serious business and we need to make sure we do not pay the price for its folly. As individuals we should love free markets because operators in them can be as incompetent as they wish.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predictions</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 14:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/predictions/</guid>
      <description>It is tough to make predictions, especially about the future.&#xA;-Yogi Berra</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Futurist Speaks to CPAs</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/joa-futurist-speaks-to-cpas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2010 14:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/joa-futurist-speaks-to-cpas/</guid>
      <description>Some economic predictions from a &amp;ldquo;strategic forecaster&amp;rdquo; named Pierce Snyder at an AICPA meeting in New Orleans. One can only hope that his prediction on government deleveraging (a nice way of saying debt retirement) is true. The others aren&amp;rsquo;t really a huge shock but interesting nonetheless.&#xA;Snyder listed seven economic inevitabilities for the next seven to eight years. Those are: * The entry-level labor pool will shrink by 5%. Workers 16 to 24 years old will be in short supply with intense competition among employers to attract this more tech-savvy generation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The War Universe</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/the-war-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 21:16:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/the-war-universe/</guid>
      <description>This is a war universe. War all the time. That is its nature. There may be other universes based on all sorts of other principles, but ours seems to be based on war and games.&#xA;-William S. Burroughs, Grand Street, No. 37 (1991)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benford&#39;s Law</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/benfords-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 01:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/benfords-law/</guid>
      <description>My wife tells me my blog is boring because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have enough pictures&amp;hellip;and also it&amp;rsquo;s about accounting. So, with that in mind, I am prepared to blow your mind with this post, pictures and all. Benford&amp;rsquo;s Law. Who&amp;rsquo;s heard of it? Anybody. Anybody. Bueller&amp;hellip;. This is Benford&amp;rsquo;s Law.&#xA;What, equations don&amp;rsquo;t do it for you? Well then, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in. Benford&amp;rsquo;s Law is one of those things that can be proven mathematically, but flies in the face of common sense.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stanford International Bank Fraud</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/stanford-international-bank-sib-fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 12:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/stanford-international-bank-sib-fraud/</guid>
      <description>While Bernie Madoff was busy having his face shown all over the news last year, a smaller but equally devastating Ponzi scheme was discovered by federal authorities: Standford International Bank (&amp;ldquo;SIB&amp;rdquo;). Because of the dollars involved in Madoff&amp;rsquo;s scam ($65 billion), the Stanford fraud ($7.2 billion) didn&amp;rsquo;t get much press coverage. However, for the victims of this fraud, the outcome may be worse.&#xA;Stanford International Bank was started in 1986 by Allen Stanford.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Daily Dish: A Taxpayer Receipt</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/the-daily-dish-a-taxpayer-receipt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 15:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/the-daily-dish-a-taxpayer-receipt/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about the blog but I thought this post from The Daily Dish was an interesting way of showing where our federal tax dollars go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Darth JEDAR</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/darth-jedar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 23:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/darth-jedar/</guid>
      <description>I found this picture in a pile of papers under my stairs and it reminded me of a fun memory so I thought I would share. While working at D&amp;amp;T, I was stationed for the better part of a year on one large client. During that period, I spent more time with those people than I did with my wife. We got to know each other well, and as would be expected with long hours and tough deadlines, some nicknames emerged.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Light Reading</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/some-light-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 15:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/some-light-reading/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick rundown of the blogs that have recently inspired my work. I digest a huge number of RSS feeds each week, and it takes a good headline for me to open (and read) a post. These blogs consistently deliver.&#xA;Seth&amp;rsquo;s Blog - Seth Godin really doesn&amp;rsquo;t need an introduction. At least not from me. He is a king of metaphor and I find his blog to be inspired. Flowing Data - Lots of good insight for data geeks and people who, like me, make their living producing compelling infographics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crypto and Backdoors</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/crypto-and-backdoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 01:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/crypto-and-backdoors/</guid>
      <description>Steve Gibson and Leo Laporte did a great podcast this week regarding the Obama administration&amp;rsquo;s proposed crypto-backdoor legislation. This is same issue Schneier discussed in his post from last week. Here are my takeaways.&#xA;The technology for strong encryption already exists. It&amp;rsquo;s math. Bad guys will still use it. Backdoor mandates will only hurt law abiding citizens. If this passes as requested by law enforcement, secure peer-to-peer communication would become illegal and the systems that support it subject to redesign.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bruce Schneier on Wiretapping the Internet</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/bruce-schneier-on-wiretapping-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 14:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/bruce-schneier-on-wiretapping-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>For those who&amp;rsquo;ve never heard of him Bruce Schneier is a cryptography expert (notably created the Blowfish block cipher and Solitaire stream cipher). He authors a good blog on info security issues and recently had a post about Obama&amp;rsquo;s internet wiretapping proposal. This is a bad idea for all sorts of reasons and Schneier does a good job outlining the risks. CPAs, especially those in IT audit functions, should pay attention to how this issue progresses as this could have substantial compliance ramifications for clients in all industries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tennessean: &#39;Crack Tax&#39; Refund</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/tennessean-crack-tax-refund/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 22:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/tennessean-crack-tax-refund/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s Tennessean had an eye catching headline: &amp;ldquo;2,772 people could be eligible for &amp;lsquo;crack tax&amp;rsquo; refunds in TN&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;You read that correctly, a &amp;lsquo;crack tax&amp;rsquo; refund. From reading the article, it seems our Department of Revenue had been assessing a property tax on crack cocaine dealers. They even &amp;ldquo;chased people down at the courthouse to get gold chains&amp;rdquo; to collect it. I knew tax revenues were down, but&amp;hellip;seriously? Well, it turns out state law doesn&amp;rsquo;t view crack dealers as &amp;ldquo;merchants&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;peddlers&amp;rdquo;, and now they all get refunds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Economist: Someone Will Pay</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/the-economist-someone-will-pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 18:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/the-economist-someone-will-pay/</guid>
      <description>This chart and article from The Economist does a great job illustrating the reasons for my views on the Bush tax cuts which I shared yesterday. The federal government has two options: reduce spending or increase taxes. I don&amp;rsquo;t see the former happening regardless of which political party is in power. The majority of the federal budget is defense and entitlements, neither of which are likely to change materially without major policy adjustments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NYT: What the Rich Don’t Need</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/nyt-what-the-rich-dont-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 13:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/nyt-what-the-rich-dont-need/</guid>
      <description>This snippet is from the New York Times this morning. The article is about the current debate to extend the Bush tax cuts or let them expire. This quote made me laugh.&#xA;There is another possible argument for including the rich in these tax cuts, one based on “fairness.” By this reasoning, the wealthy are entitled to low tax rates because they have temporarily had them, and it would now be unfair to take them back.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WSJ: Sliced Bagels, Taxes on Top</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/wsj-sliced-bagels-taxes-on-top/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 18:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/wsj-sliced-bagels-taxes-on-top/</guid>
      <description>The WSJ had an interesting article today about a quirk in New York&amp;rsquo;s sales tax code. Under current rules, prepared foods are taxed at a higher rate than unprepared foods. On the surface this seems logical. Rich people eat out, poor people don&amp;rsquo;t, and if the goal is a progressive tax system, this would seem a reasonable distinction. The problem then becomes how one defines a prepared food versus unprepared.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Google Fusion Tables Helped Me Look Awesome</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/how-google-fusion-tables-helped-me-look-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 14:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/how-google-fusion-tables-helped-me-look-awesome/</guid>
      <description>Last Monday I came into work to find a surprise: a memo seeking clarification of a business decision we had made in opening a new location. Lots of issues were wrapped up in the questions this memo raised, but the bottom line was I needed to prove this new location would not hurt sales at an existing location where the company has a large stake.&#xA;I had customer level data for all our locations which included geolocation information (city, state, zip code, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Loopholes</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/game-loopholes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 13:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/game-loopholes/</guid>
      <description>Most of my daily life involves using numbers at work. However, numbers also have a significant role in my play. As a kid, I was a baseball card collector: bought them, traded them, memorized them. I think I liked baseball cards not for the personalities they represented, but because of the data on the back. All games involve numbers. Games of chance, games of skill: it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter. Numbers are the way we measure performance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nowadays, Everyone Is a Geek</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/nowadays-everyone-is-a-geek/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 16:15:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/nowadays-everyone-is-a-geek/</guid>
      <description>These days everyone is calling themselves a geek. Somewhere along the way, it became a fashionable term. With the rise of the mobile web and modern day social networking, everyone, it seems, is into technology. Welcome newcomers. It was not always so. Geeks have been around looooong before it was fashionable. In fact, I was a geek before the average man even knew what the internet was. The world wide web was only used by institutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Appeals Court Overturns Taxpayer Win in Tax Shelter Case</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/joa-appeals-court-overturns-taxpayer-win-in-tax-shelter-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 15:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/joa-appeals-court-overturns-taxpayer-win-in-tax-shelter-case/</guid>
      <description>Most people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t root for the IRS in a court case, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad to see this decision. How long before we see &amp;ldquo;Grandson of BOSS&amp;rdquo; tax shelter schemes?&#xA;The U.S. Court of Appeals for the Tenth Circuit has held that a taxpayer’s investment in a “Son of BOSS” tax shelter lacked economic substance and therefore did not generate deductible losses. This holding reverses a rare taxpayer win on the issue of Son of BOSS tax shelters in which a district court had allowed the taxpayer to deduct losses from the investment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Browsing via Linux: Prudent or Paranoid</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/web-browsing-via-linux-prudent-or-paranoid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 18:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/web-browsing-via-linux-prudent-or-paranoid/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I was listening to a podcast called Security Now! (which you should check out by the way). Steve Gibson, the host, mentioned a recently discovered Windows vulnerability that has been present in the OS going back 10+ years. Needless to say this was a little concerning that a vulnerability could exist for so long without being noticed, much less patched.&#xA;Microsoft has since rolled out a patch that plugs the hole, but the question remains, &amp;ldquo;Should I be surfing the web in the same OS I use to manage my finances and other sensitive info?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top Five Android Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/07/top-five-android-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2010 03:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/07/top-five-android-apps/</guid>
      <description>This is normally an accounting blog, but, (as I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;ve figured out) I am also a bit of a tech geek. Recently, I got my first real smartphone, a Motorola Droid. The Droid has been a game changer for me and I really can&amp;rsquo;t imagine where this technology will be in another 5-10 years. That said, I thought I would throw my two cents in regarding my top five favorite apps I have come across so far.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s a New Sheriff in Town...or Two.</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/07/theres-a-new-sheriff-in-town-or-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2010 13:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/07/theres-a-new-sheriff-in-town-or-two/</guid>
      <description>Last week, the Senate approved some substantial overhauls to the financial regulatory system. The landscape is about to change and CPAs will need to know who the new sheriffs are. As best I can tell, we gained two new agencies and lost one.&#xA;The first is the Financial Stability Oversight Council. This is group that will be charged with identifying companies, products or activities that pose a &amp;ldquo;systemic risk&amp;rdquo; to the economy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keynes vs. Hayek Rap Video</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/07/keynes-vs-hayek-rap-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2010 12:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/07/keynes-vs-hayek-rap-video/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit, sometimes the content on this site can be a little dry. I came across a video this week I thought might add a little humor. Anyone who takes Econ 101 hears about John Maynard Keynes, Milton Friedman, and F.A. Hayek. Ususally, our introduction to these individuals is in the form of a documentary film of some sort, complete with a British narrator, Ken Burns Effect photo zooming, and a long enough run time to complete a short nap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Little Change for PCAOB Under High Court Ruling</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/joa-little-change-for-pcaob-under-high-court-ruling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 14:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/joa-little-change-for-pcaob-under-high-court-ruling/</guid>
      <description>This was the outcome I expected, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure some audit firm partners, controllers and CFOs were hoping for something a little more earth-shattering.&#xA;The Supreme Court’s 5–4 decision Monday in the constitutional challenge to the PCAOB will leave the agency virtually unchanged. The court’s ruling will not affect day-to-day operations of the PCAOB, the agency said. Chief Justice John Roberts wrote the majority opinion. In it, he said the court was isolating, or “severing,” from the rest of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act the one constitutional flaw the court found regarding the power to remove PCAOB members.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Managing Well</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/the-art-of-managing-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 17:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/the-art-of-managing-well/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I believe managing is like holding a dove in your hand. If you hold it too tightly you kill it, but if you hold it too loosely, you lose it.&amp;rdquo; -Tommy Lasorda&#xA;There is an art to managing well. I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit I am still learning. As I have been given positions of leadership, one of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to do is look back on leaders I admire for traits to emulate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Supreme Court Expected to Rule Soon on PCAOB&#39;s Constitutionality</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/joa-supreme-court-expected-to-rule-soon-on-pcaobs-constitutionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2010 20:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/joa-supreme-court-expected-to-rule-soon-on-pcaobs-constitutionality/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court is set to rule soon on a case that could theoretically invalidate the PCAOB and (potentially) all of Sarbanes-Oxley. This month&amp;rsquo;s Journal of Accountancy has an article that does a great job laying out what is at stake.&#xA;Because the Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) does not contain a severability clause, a provision that allows one part of a law to be struck down while keeping the other provisions in force, some observers have pointed out that the entire law could be invalidated by the Supreme Court, which would eliminate the funding of FASB under SOX section 109 and regulations regarding internal control over financial reporting under section 404.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HBR: Does Tax Time Need To Be So Taxing?</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/04/hbr-does-tax-time-need-to-be-so-taxing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 14:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/04/hbr-does-tax-time-need-to-be-so-taxing/</guid>
      <description>The Commissioner of the IRS uses a paid preparer for his tax return…..Really?&#xA;So, I ask again, what’s going on? Here’s one possibility: Over the years, the government turned the tax code over to technical experts, who wrote the regulations, forms, and processes in their own language without regard for the end-user, the citizen, who would be required to use them. As the language and process became more and more arcane, fewer end-users could actually do their own taxes, so an industry of “tax preparers” formed to provide an interface between the tax payer and the taxing authorities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Access VBA: Starting from Ground Zero</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/03/access-vba-starting-from-ground-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 13:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/03/access-vba-starting-from-ground-zero/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I have been getting out my comfort zone with SAS/SQL and expanding into the world of Visual Basic. For those unfamiliar, Visual Basic for Applications (or VBA) is Microsoft’s language which allows users to customize Microsoft Office. It is especially useful in Access and Excel. A simple example of VBA would be an Excel macro. When a user records a macro, the steps are recorded as VBA code and mapped to a keyboard shortcut.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frontline: Tax Me If You Can</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/12/there-is-a-fantastic-episode-from-the-pb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2009 14:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/12/there-is-a-fantastic-episode-from-the-pb/</guid>
      <description>There is a fantastic episode from the PBS series Frontline called &amp;ldquo;Tax Me If You Can&amp;rdquo; which I originally saw in 2005 while working on my MACC degree. It&amp;rsquo;s all about the business of tax shelters: the people who buy them and the people who create, market and sell them. I revisit the episode at least once a year just for the sheer entertainment value. PBS still has episode online in its entirety.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DO Loops: Part Deux (It&#39;s a pun. Get it?)</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/12/do-loops-part-deux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 18:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/12/do-loops-part-deux/</guid>
      <description>For Part II in this series of posts on DO Loops in SAS, I wanted to discuss an application slightly more complex than the previous example. Loops can not only be used to perform data correction (as shown in the previous post), but can also be very useful in creating new records where none exist. We’ll discuss using order data again as our example. Your client would like you to create a daily trend report showing YTD Quantity Sold by Product by Date.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DO Loops: Useful Tool in SAS User&#39;s Toolbox</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/12/do-loops-a-powerful-tool-in-sas-users-toolbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2009 15:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/12/do-loops-a-powerful-tool-in-sas-users-toolbox/</guid>
      <description>DO Loops in SAS are outside the scope of what most beginning users feel comfortable tackling. However, they are a powerful, time-saving tool in the report writer’s toolbox. For those unfamiliar with programming, loops are a set of instructions that the programmer tells the computer to repeat until predefined condition(s) are true. It’s a simple concept but powerful in execution.&#xA;To illustrate, here is an example of where a loop might be used.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Actuarial Triangle: Powerful Tool for Accounting Estimates</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/11/actuarial-triangle-powerful-tool-for-accounting-estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 19:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/11/actuarial-triangle-powerful-tool-for-accounting-estimates/</guid>
      <description>When individuals outside the profession think of accounting, they don&amp;rsquo;t often consider its subjective nature. Most people assume there are bright line rules and it&amp;rsquo;s the CPA&amp;rsquo;s job to make sure the rules are adhered to. In some instances, there is exact guidance (which makes our lives easier), but in many others CPAs are required to make estimates. Estimates being a nice way of saying, &amp;ldquo;Mr. CPA, please attempt to predict the future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;I should have done more.&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/11/i-should-have-done-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 01:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/11/i-should-have-done-more/</guid>
      <description>Listened to a podcast this afternoon from &amp;ldquo;This American Life&amp;rdquo; entitled &amp;ldquo;Return to the Giant Pool of Money&amp;rdquo;. The series&amp;rsquo; first episode contains the best explanation of last fall&amp;rsquo;s financial meltdown I have heard. The &amp;ldquo;return&amp;rdquo; was equally informative. While the podcast contained interviews with many different players, the most interesting character, in my opinion, was Glen.&#xA;Glen was a mortgage company sales manager during the boom. He stated in the first part of the series that during the good times he was netting upwards of 75-100K per month in income.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excel Protect Sheet Hack</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/02/excel-protect-sheet-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 15:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/02/excel-protect-sheet-hack/</guid>
      <description>I had a situation yesterday where I was trying to get into a password protected Excel sheet and did not know the password. After a quick Google search I realized that the &amp;ldquo;Protect Sheet&amp;rdquo; function in Excel has a backdoor which can be exploited with a few lines of VBA. I didn&amp;rsquo;t write the code below, but I am not ashamed to use it.&#xA;The algorithm relies on a backdoor password that can be 1 to 9 characters long where each character is either an &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; except the last which can be any character from ASCII code 32 to 255.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple Standards Sound Solid</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2008/02/simple-standards-sound-solid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 21:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2008/02/simple-standards-sound-solid/</guid>
      <description>While standard setting in the accounting world is not exactly glamorous, it is, at times, fascinating. This last month the Journal of Accountancy contained an interview with Robert Herz, FASB&amp;rsquo;s current chairman, where he discussed some of the changes coming down the road. The gist of the article was that everything we learned in school will be different (and hopefully simpler) within five to ten years.&#xA;Having experienced the headaches of auditing companies that report using both international standards and GAAP, I, for one, am excited about the eventual convergence of standards.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accounting, Finance Salaries on the Rise</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/12/accounting-finance-salaries-on-the-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2007 20:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/12/accounting-finance-salaries-on-the-rise/</guid>
      <description>It is always nice to read an article like this about your profession. Robert Half International has come up with these salary estimates for the following accounting/finance positions in 2008.&#xA;Internal auditor. National average starting salaries for internal audit managers at large companies (more than $250 million in sales) are expected to climb 6.7 percent in 2008, to a range of $81,500 to $109,500 annually. Senior accountant. The greatest gains in starting compensation for senior accountants are expected at midsize companies ($25 million to $250 million in sales), with starting salaries projected to rise 5.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If It Looks Like a Duck...</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/12/if-it-looks-like-a-duck/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2007 17:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/12/if-it-looks-like-a-duck/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished a book on the Enron scandal entitled, &amp;ldquo;The Smartest Guys in the Room.&amp;rdquo; It was a fantastic book and, for the accounting geeks, had good descriptions of the related party transactions that Enron used to prop up their earnings during the late 90s. The SPEs had really fun names like Chewco and Jedi and Whitewing. Inside, I think Fastow must have been a Star Wars fanboy. Amidst all the accounting and structured finance shenanigans, there was a paragraph from an employee that summarized the entire meltdown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/11/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2007 22:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/11/first-post/</guid>
      <description>I enjoy numbers. I like adding them and subtracting them, moving them around and finding patterns. This is a blog about that. I am a CPA so I will occasionally throw in my thoughts on the profession. Hopefully it will be somewhat insightful and not completely narcissistic. Happy reading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Certified Public Accountant and Financial Systems leader in Nashville&amp;rsquo;s healthcare industry. My current role is Head of Financial Business Systems at Lyra Health. I am an experienced people manager, and enjoy training on the intersection of accounting and technology.&#xA;I have deep experience with a variety of platforms and tools including the following.&#xA;Accounting Avalara Cognos Coupa NetSuite Salesforce SmartStream Symbeo ZoneCapture Zuora Data &amp;amp; Analytics Business Objects dbt Core Microsoft SQL Server PostgreSQL SAS Snowflake Tableau Workato DevOps Jira Docker GitHub / GitLab GnuPG SSH / SFTP Healthcare Advantx Centricity eClinicalWorks NextGen SIS Vision Programming Bash Python PowerShell SAS SQL </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Send me an email.&#xA;For those that are so inclined, here is my PGP public key.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>Specialties ERP system administration Leading and coaching high performing teams Purchase accounting and consolidation Multi-currency reporting Healthcare accounting Sarbanes-Oxley Preparation of financial statements and executive reporting packages Budgeting and forecasting Data analysis and analytics Leveraging technological infrastructure to drive efficiencies and profitability Experience Lyra Health&#xA;Head of Financial Business Systems, 5/21 - present&#xA;Lead the Financial Business Systems team. Lyra&amp;rsquo;s users and operations span six continents. My role is to define systems strategy for the consolidated global enterprise.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
