<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jared Monger</title>
    <link>https://www.jmonger.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jared Monger</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.jmonger.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a financial systems leader and Certified Public Accountant in Nashville&amp;rsquo;s healthcare industry. My current role is Head of Financial Business Systems at Lyra Health, a global EAP with operations on six continents. Prior to Lyra, I spent many years with AMSURG as well as Deloitte. I am an experienced people manager, and enjoy training on the intersection of accounting and technology.&#xA;My specialties include ERP administration, consolidation, systems integration, and data engineering.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Send me an email.&#xA;For those that are so inclined, here is my PGP public key.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>Specialties Link to heading ERP system administration Leading and coaching high performing teams Purchase accounting and consolidation Multi-currency reporting Healthcare accounting Sarbanes-Oxley Preparation of financial statements and executive reporting packages Budgeting and forecasting Data engineering and analytics Leveraging technological infrastructure to drive efficiencies and profitability Experience Link to heading Lyra Health&#xA;Head of Financial Business Systems, 5/21 - present&#xA;I currently lead the Financial Business Systems team at Lyra Health.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
