<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tax on Jared Monger</title>
    <link>https://www.jmonger.com/tags/tax/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tax on Jared Monger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 15:11:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.jmonger.com/tags/tax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Appeals Court Overturns Taxpayer Win in Tax Shelter Case</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/joa-appeals-court-overturns-taxpayer-win-in-tax-shelter-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 15:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/joa-appeals-court-overturns-taxpayer-win-in-tax-shelter-case/</guid>
      <description>Most people wouldn&#39;t root for the IRS in a court case, but I&#39;m glad to see this decision. How long before we see &amp;ldquo;Grandson of BOSS&amp;rdquo; tax shelter schemes?
 The U.S. Court of Appeals for the Tenth Circuit has held that a taxpayer’s investment in a “Son of BOSS” tax shelter lacked economic substance and therefore did not generate deductible losses. This holding reverses a rare taxpayer win on the issue of Son of BOSS tax shelters in which a district court had allowed the taxpayer to deduct losses from the investment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HBR: Does Tax Time Need To Be So Taxing?</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/04/hbr-does-tax-time-need-to-be-so-taxing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 14:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/04/hbr-does-tax-time-need-to-be-so-taxing/</guid>
      <description>The Commissioner of the IRS uses a paid preparer for his tax return…..Really?
 So, I ask again, what’s going on? Here’s one possibility: Over the years, the government turned the tax code over to technical experts, who wrote the regulations, forms, and processes in their own language without regard for the end-user, the citizen, who would be required to use them. As the language and process became more and more arcane, fewer end-users could actually do their own taxes, so an industry of “tax preparers” formed to provide an interface between the tax payer and the taxing authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>