<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tax on Jared Monger</title>
    <link>https://www.jmonger.com/tags/tax/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tax on Jared Monger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 21:07:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.jmonger.com/tags/tax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Provisions in the Senate&#39;s Tax Cut Extension Bill</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/joa-provisions-in-the-senates-tax-cut-extension-bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 21:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/joa-provisions-in-the-senates-tax-cut-extension-bill/</guid>
      <description>In case you were curious about the exact provisions in the Senate&#39;s tax bill the Journal of Accountancy has a detailed article.
 The bill has provisions from four of the five tax areas that were considered to be important for Congress to address during its current “lame duck” session: the estate tax, expiring tax cuts, expired tax provisions, and an alternative minimum tax (AMT) patch. The bill as introduced does not address the expanded Form 1099 reporting requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Whose Goodwill Is It?</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/joa-whose-goodwill-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 14:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/joa-whose-goodwill-is-it/</guid>
      <description>This is interesting. Not sure I agree with the ruling. However, my father is a dentist who&#39;s owned his practice for 25+ years, so I&#39;m a little biased.
 The U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Washington recently held that goodwill created while a dentist was employed by his solely owned corporation belonged to the corporation and not to him. As a result, the dentist was required to characterize as a corporate dividend rather than a long-term capital gain the amount he received for the goodwill from the sale of his practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Daily Dish: A Taxpayer Receipt</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/the-daily-dish-a-taxpayer-receipt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 15:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/the-daily-dish-a-taxpayer-receipt/</guid>
      <description>Don&#39;t know anything about the blog but I thought this post from The Daily Dish was an interesting way of showing where our federal tax dollars go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tennessean: &#39;Crack Tax&#39; Refund</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/tennessean-crack-tax-refund/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 22:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/tennessean-crack-tax-refund/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s Tennessean had an eye catching headline: &amp;ldquo;2,772 people could be eligible for &amp;lsquo;crack tax&amp;rsquo; refunds in TN&amp;rdquo;.
You read that correctly, a &amp;lsquo;crack tax&amp;rsquo; refund. From reading the article, it seems our Department of Revenue had been assessing a property tax on crack cocaine dealers. They even &amp;ldquo;chased people down at the courthouse to get gold chains&amp;rdquo; to collect it. I knew tax revenues were down, but&amp;hellip;seriously? Well, it turns out state law doesn&#39;t view crack dealers as &amp;ldquo;merchants&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;peddlers&amp;rdquo;, and now they all get refunds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Economist: Someone Will Pay</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/the-economist-someone-will-pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 18:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/the-economist-someone-will-pay/</guid>
      <description>This chart and article from The Economist does a great job illustrating the reasons for my views on the Bush tax cuts which I shared yesterday. The federal government has two options: reduce spending or increase taxes. I don&#39;t see the former happening regardless of which political party is in power. The majority of the federal budget is defense and entitlements, neither of which are likely to change materially without major policy adjustments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYT: What the Rich Don’t Need</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/nyt-what-the-rich-dont-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 13:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/nyt-what-the-rich-dont-need/</guid>
      <description>This snippet is from the New York Times this morning. The article is about the current debate to extend the Bush tax cuts or let them expire. This quote made me laugh.
 There is another possible argument for including the rich in these tax cuts, one based on “fairness.” By this reasoning, the wealthy are entitled to low tax rates because they have temporarily had them, and it would now be unfair to take them back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WSJ: Sliced Bagels, Taxes on Top</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/wsj-sliced-bagels-taxes-on-top/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 18:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/wsj-sliced-bagels-taxes-on-top/</guid>
      <description>The WSJ had an interesting article today about a quirk in New York&#39;s sales tax code. Under current rules, prepared foods are taxed at a higher rate than unprepared foods. On the surface this seems logical. Rich people eat out, poor people don&#39;t, and if the goal is a progressive tax system, this would seem a reasonable distinction. The problem then becomes how one defines a prepared food versus unprepared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Appeals Court Overturns Taxpayer Win in Tax Shelter Case</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/joa-appeals-court-overturns-taxpayer-win-in-tax-shelter-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 15:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/joa-appeals-court-overturns-taxpayer-win-in-tax-shelter-case/</guid>
      <description>Most people wouldn&#39;t root for the IRS in a court case, but I&#39;m glad to see this decision. How long before we see &amp;ldquo;Grandson of BOSS&amp;rdquo; tax shelter schemes?
 The U.S. Court of Appeals for the Tenth Circuit has held that a taxpayer’s investment in a “Son of BOSS” tax shelter lacked economic substance and therefore did not generate deductible losses. This holding reverses a rare taxpayer win on the issue of Son of BOSS tax shelters in which a district court had allowed the taxpayer to deduct losses from the investment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HBR: Does Tax Time Need To Be So Taxing?</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/04/hbr-does-tax-time-need-to-be-so-taxing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 14:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/04/hbr-does-tax-time-need-to-be-so-taxing/</guid>
      <description>The Commissioner of the IRS uses a paid preparer for his tax return…..Really?
 So, I ask again, what’s going on? Here’s one possibility: Over the years, the government turned the tax code over to technical experts, who wrote the regulations, forms, and processes in their own language without regard for the end-user, the citizen, who would be required to use them. As the language and process became more and more arcane, fewer end-users could actually do their own taxes, so an industry of “tax preparers” formed to provide an interface between the tax payer and the taxing authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frontline: Tax Me If You Can</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/12/there-is-a-fantastic-episode-from-the-pb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2009 14:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/12/there-is-a-fantastic-episode-from-the-pb/</guid>
      <description>There is a fantastic episode from the PBS series Frontline called &amp;ldquo;Tax Me If You Can&amp;rdquo; which I originally saw in 2005 while working on my MACC degree. It&#39;s all about the business of tax shelters: the people who buy them and the people who create, market and sell them. I revisit the episode at least once a year just for the sheer entertainment value. PBS still has episode online in its entirety.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>