<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Profession on Jared Monger</title>
    <link>https://www.jmonger.com/tags/profession/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Profession on Jared Monger</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.1</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 20:37:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.jmonger.com/tags/profession/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Can You Teach Ethics?</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/11/can-you-teach-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 20:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/11/can-you-teach-ethics/</guid>
      <description>CPAs across the country are required to sit through various amounts of ethics training every two years. I sat thought mine on Friday. Inevitably during these sessions, the question comes up, &amp;ldquo;Can ethics be taught?&amp;rdquo; My own answer to this question has fluctuated since it was first posed to me as a graduate student. Could more effective ethics training have prevented the major accounting failures of the last 10 years? I am, by nature and temperament, a realist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everybody Stay Calm</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/11/everybody-stay-calm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 14:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/11/everybody-stay-calm/</guid>
      <description>You may have noticed the blog posts have been in short supply since last year. Well, frankly, it&amp;rsquo;s because I&amp;rsquo;ve been a lot busier and the nature of my work has changed significantly. Instead of spending hours debugging code and writing the perfect formula in Excel, I&amp;rsquo;m now delegating responsibilities and managing people. This has been an exciting and different world for me. As far as my plans for this blog, I&amp;rsquo;m still going to post the odd technical tip as projects come up, but I may shift some focus to current accounting news and people management since that&amp;rsquo;s where I am spending my time these days.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Problem With College</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/10/the-problem-with-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2011 19:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/10/the-problem-with-college/</guid>
      <description>Much of the discussion surrounding the Occupy Wall Street protest movement has turned towards the rising costs of higher education. This is likely because many of the protesters are young, college educated and saddled with enormous federal debt. The Los Angeles Times had a piece this weekend discussing the issue. It was good article, but I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed something missing in all the coverage. Something that colleges, students and even parents don&amp;rsquo;t seem to want to talk about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should Accountants Be Required to Code</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/should-accountants-be-required-to-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 17:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/should-accountants-be-required-to-code/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, I wonder where I fit on the career spectrum. I am trained as a CPA and 90% of my daily work involves accounting in some form. However, I am also a programmer who geeks out when I find a new way to automate processes or transform data into knowledge. My boss made a comment a few weeks ago in a meeting, “If you want to get Jared excited, ask him about two things: 1) His family or 2) SAS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HBR: Why It&#39;s Better to Be Smart and Wrong than Just Silent</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/hbr-why-its-better-to-be-smart-and-wrong-than-just-silent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 21:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/hbr-why-its-better-to-be-smart-and-wrong-than-just-silent/</guid>
      <description>I received this same advice from a senior auditor in a performance review four years ago. It is some of the best career advice I&amp;rsquo;ve ever received.&#xA;When you&amp;rsquo;re not sure what to do or how to proceed, don&amp;rsquo;t start with a blank slate and ask for help. Instead, start with what you do know, state your intended direction (and rationale behind it) and then get the buy-in or feedback of your manager.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Managing Well</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/the-art-of-managing-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 17:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/the-art-of-managing-well/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I believe managing is like holding a dove in your hand. If you hold it too tightly you kill it, but if you hold it too loosely, you lose it.&amp;rdquo; -Tommy Lasorda&#xA;There is an art to managing well. I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit I am still learning. As I have been given positions of leadership, one of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to do is look back on leaders I admire for traits to emulate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;I should have done more.&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/11/i-should-have-done-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 01:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/11/i-should-have-done-more/</guid>
      <description>Listened to a podcast this afternoon from &amp;ldquo;This American Life&amp;rdquo; entitled &amp;ldquo;Return to the Giant Pool of Money&amp;rdquo;. The series&amp;rsquo; first episode contains the best explanation of last fall&amp;rsquo;s financial meltdown I have heard. The &amp;ldquo;return&amp;rdquo; was equally informative. While the podcast contained interviews with many different players, the most interesting character, in my opinion, was Glen.&#xA;Glen was a mortgage company sales manager during the boom. He stated in the first part of the series that during the good times he was netting upwards of 75-100K per month in income.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accounting, Finance Salaries on the Rise</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/12/accounting-finance-salaries-on-the-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2007 20:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/12/accounting-finance-salaries-on-the-rise/</guid>
      <description>It is always nice to read an article like this about your profession. Robert Half International has come up with these salary estimates for the following accounting/finance positions in 2008.&#xA;Internal auditor. National average starting salaries for internal audit managers at large companies (more than $250 million in sales) are expected to climb 6.7 percent in 2008, to a range of $81,500 to $109,500 annually. Senior accountant. The greatest gains in starting compensation for senior accountants are expected at midsize companies ($25 million to $250 million in sales), with starting salaries projected to rise 5.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/11/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2007 22:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/11/first-post/</guid>
      <description>I enjoy numbers. I like adding them and subtracting them, moving them around and finding patterns. This is a blog about that. I am a CPA so I will occasionally throw in my thoughts on the profession. Hopefully it will be somewhat insightful and not completely narcissistic. Happy reading.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
