<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Jared Monger</title>
    <link>https://www.jmonger.com/tags/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Jared Monger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 18:42:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jmonger.com/tags/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sino-Forest, Short Sellers Allege Ponzi Scheme</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/06/sino-forest-short-sellers-allege-ponzi-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 18:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/06/sino-forest-short-sellers-allege-ponzi-scheme/</guid>
      <description>There is an interesting alleged accounting fraud unfolding in China. Sino-Forest Corporation, a Chinese company in the business of selling timber, has been accused by short sellers of being a massive Ponzi scheme. Like Enron, they seem to be running their business through a complex system of subsidiaries in order to obfuscate transactions. One of the funnier quotes from the short sellers&#39; report is below:
 Despite TRE’s opacity on the revenue side, we have overwhelming evidence that the $231.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin: A Money Launderer&#39;s Dream Come True</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/05/bitcoin-a-money-launderers-dream-come-true/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 17:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/05/bitcoin-a-money-launderers-dream-come-true/</guid>
      <description>I first heard about Bitcoin when Steve Gibson did a podcast on it a few months ago. Essentially, it&amp;rsquo;s a medium of exchange just like any other currency. The major differences are 1. &amp;ldquo;coins&amp;rdquo; are simply bits in the system with no physical reality (actually, most of the US money supply has no physical reality either, but that&amp;rsquo;s a post for another day), 2. transfers can&amp;rsquo;t be traced, and 3. there is little to no transaction cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s All Good. At Least Until The Robots Learn the Nuclear Launch Codes.</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/ken-jennings-its-all-good-at-least-until-the-robots-learn-the-nuclear-launch-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 16:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/ken-jennings-its-all-good-at-least-until-the-robots-learn-the-nuclear-launch-codes/</guid>
      <description>Slate has an article from Ken Jennings talking about his match this week against IBM&amp;rsquo;s Watson Supercomputer. This was my favorite quote.
 So my defeat at the hands of a machine has a happy ending, after all. At least until the whole system becomes sentient and figures out the nuclear launch codes. But I figure that&amp;rsquo;s years away.
 Pretty soon we&amp;rsquo;ll all need some Old Glory Insurance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wired: Cracking the Scratch Lottery Code</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/wired-cracking-the-scratch-lottery-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 14:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/wired-cracking-the-scratch-lottery-code/</guid>
      <description>This was an interesting story from Wired about a Canadian statistician who cracked the Ontario lottery scratch-off algorithm.
 The apparent randomness of the scratch ticket was just a facade, a mathematical lie. And this meant that the lottery system might actually be solvable, just like those mining samples. “At the time, I had no intention of cracking the tickets,” he says. He was just curious about the algorithm that produced the numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYT: Still Digging</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/nyt-still-digging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 17:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/nyt-still-digging/</guid>
      <description>From Thomas Friedman. I love this.
 More than ever, America today reminds me of a working couple where the husband has just lost his job, they have two kids in junior high school, a mortgage and they’re maxed out on their credit cards. On top of it all, they recently agreed to take in their troubled cousin, Kabul, who just can’t get his act together and keeps bouncing from relative to relative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYT: Ireland Parliament to Vote on Austere Budget</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/nyt-ireland-parliament-to-vote-on-austere-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 23:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/nyt-ireland-parliament-to-vote-on-austere-budget/</guid>
      <description>Sobering politics these days in Ireland. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure our own government would be capable of passing a budget like this.
 DUBLIN — Pressured by onerous debts and fears of financial contagion, the Irish government introduced one of the strictest budgets in the nation’s history Tuesday, raising taxes and slashing government and welfare spending to qualify for an 85 billion euro aid package from its European partners. &amp;hellip; “This is a bailout for the speculators and the financial markets of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GigaOM: Get Business Intelligence Ready for the Real-Time Web</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/gigaom-get-business-intelligence-ready-for-the-real-time-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 21:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/gigaom-get-business-intelligence-ready-for-the-real-time-web/</guid>
      <description>GigaOM had a good article this morning called Get Business Intelligence Ready for the Real-Time Web. Here&amp;rsquo;s what they say BI 2.0 should look like. Not sure the tools exist yet to accomplish, but I can see things moving in this direction. Well designed dashboards do some of this already.
 The future of BI 2.0 will not rely on server power, but on the human power of the entire organization to capture everything, convert social media into tangible business objects, and automate real-time business processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NBJ: Mortgage rates fall again</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/nbj-mortgage-rates-fall-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 17:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/nbj-mortgage-rates-fall-again/</guid>
      <description>Nashville Business Journal had a story this morning about mortgage interest rates continuing to fall. The 15 year fixed average is barely higher than average annual inflation. It&amp;rsquo;s crazy. If you are in the market for a home, now is the time. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t get any better for buyers than this.
 Long-term mortgage rates fell to new lows this week, after the Federal Reserve’s announcement to step back into the Treasuries market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYT: It’s Morning in India</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/nyt-its-morning-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 14:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/nyt-its-morning-in-india/</guid>
      <description>I enjoyed this article. I used to share projects with Deloitte&amp;rsquo;s office in Hyderabad, India. During busy season, I would work on gathering the relevant project components during the day, discuss the requirements on the phone that night, and when I came in the next morning, there in my inbox would sit the completed project. Pretty amazing, really. One gentleman worked over 400 hours during January 2008 to meet my project deadlines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Whose Goodwill Is It?</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/joa-whose-goodwill-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 14:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/joa-whose-goodwill-is-it/</guid>
      <description>This is interesting. Not sure I agree with the ruling. However, my father is a dentist who&amp;rsquo;s owned his practice for 25+ years, so I&amp;rsquo;m a little biased.
 The U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Washington recently held that goodwill created while a dentist was employed by his solely owned corporation belonged to the corporation and not to him. As a result, the dentist was required to characterize as a corporate dividend rather than a long-term capital gain the amount he received for the goodwill from the sale of his practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Futurist Speaks to CPAs</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/joa-futurist-speaks-to-cpas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2010 14:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/joa-futurist-speaks-to-cpas/</guid>
      <description>Some economic predictions from a &amp;ldquo;strategic forecaster&amp;rdquo; named Pierce Snyder at an AICPA meeting in New Orleans. One can only hope that his prediction on government deleveraging (a nice way of saying debt retirement) is true. The others aren&amp;rsquo;t really a huge shock but interesting nonetheless.
 Snyder listed seven economic inevitabilities for the next seven to eight years. Those are: * The entry-level labor pool will shrink by 5%. Workers 16 to 24 years old will be in short supply with intense competition among employers to attract this more tech-savvy generation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tennessean: &#39;Crack Tax&#39; Refund</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/tennessean-crack-tax-refund/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 22:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/tennessean-crack-tax-refund/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s Tennessean had an eye catching headline: &amp;ldquo;2,772 people could be eligible for &amp;lsquo;crack tax&amp;rsquo; refunds in TN&amp;rdquo;.
You read that correctly, a &amp;lsquo;crack tax&amp;rsquo; refund. From reading the article, it seems our Department of Revenue had been assessing a property tax on crack cocaine dealers. They even &amp;ldquo;chased people down at the courthouse to get gold chains&amp;rdquo; to collect it. I knew tax revenues were down, but&amp;hellip;seriously? Well, it turns out state law doesn&amp;rsquo;t view crack dealers as &amp;ldquo;merchants&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;peddlers&amp;rdquo;, and now they all get refunds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Economist: Someone Will Pay</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/the-economist-someone-will-pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 18:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/the-economist-someone-will-pay/</guid>
      <description>This chart and article from The Economist does a great job illustrating the reasons for my views on the Bush tax cuts which I shared yesterday. The federal government has two options: reduce spending or increase taxes. I don&amp;rsquo;t see the former happening regardless of which political party is in power. The majority of the federal budget is defense and entitlements, neither of which are likely to change materially without major policy adjustments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYT: What the Rich Don’t Need</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/nyt-what-the-rich-dont-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 13:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/09/nyt-what-the-rich-dont-need/</guid>
      <description>This snippet is from the New York Times this morning. The article is about the current debate to extend the Bush tax cuts or let them expire. This quote made me laugh.
 There is another possible argument for including the rich in these tax cuts, one based on “fairness.” By this reasoning, the wealthy are entitled to low tax rates because they have temporarily had them, and it would now be unfair to take them back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WSJ: Sliced Bagels, Taxes on Top</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/wsj-sliced-bagels-taxes-on-top/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 18:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/wsj-sliced-bagels-taxes-on-top/</guid>
      <description>The WSJ had an interesting article today about a quirk in New York&amp;rsquo;s sales tax code. Under current rules, prepared foods are taxed at a higher rate than unprepared foods. On the surface this seems logical. Rich people eat out, poor people don&amp;rsquo;t, and if the goal is a progressive tax system, this would seem a reasonable distinction. The problem then becomes how one defines a prepared food versus unprepared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Appeals Court Overturns Taxpayer Win in Tax Shelter Case</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/joa-appeals-court-overturns-taxpayer-win-in-tax-shelter-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 15:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/joa-appeals-court-overturns-taxpayer-win-in-tax-shelter-case/</guid>
      <description>Most people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t root for the IRS in a court case, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad to see this decision. How long before we see &amp;ldquo;Grandson of BOSS&amp;rdquo; tax shelter schemes?
 The U.S. Court of Appeals for the Tenth Circuit has held that a taxpayer’s investment in a “Son of BOSS” tax shelter lacked economic substance and therefore did not generate deductible losses. This holding reverses a rare taxpayer win on the issue of Son of BOSS tax shelters in which a district court had allowed the taxpayer to deduct losses from the investment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s a New Sheriff in Town...or Two.</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/07/theres-a-new-sheriff-in-town-or-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2010 13:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/07/theres-a-new-sheriff-in-town-or-two/</guid>
      <description>Last week, the Senate approved some substantial overhauls to the financial regulatory system. The landscape is about to change and CPAs will need to know who the new sheriffs are. As best I can tell, we gained two new agencies and lost one.
The first is the Financial Stability Oversight Council. This is group that will be charged with identifying companies, products or activities that pose a &amp;ldquo;systemic risk&amp;rdquo; to the economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Little Change for PCAOB Under High Court Ruling</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/joa-little-change-for-pcaob-under-high-court-ruling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 14:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/joa-little-change-for-pcaob-under-high-court-ruling/</guid>
      <description>This was the outcome I expected, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure some audit firm partners, controllers and CFOs were hoping for something a little more earth-shattering.
 The Supreme Court’s 5–4 decision Monday in the constitutional challenge to the PCAOB will leave the agency virtually unchanged. The court’s ruling will not affect day-to-day operations of the PCAOB, the agency said. Chief Justice John Roberts wrote the majority opinion. In it, he said the court was isolating, or “severing,” from the rest of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act the one constitutional flaw the court found regarding the power to remove PCAOB members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Supreme Court Expected to Rule Soon on PCAOB&#39;s Constitutionality</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/joa-supreme-court-expected-to-rule-soon-on-pcaobs-constitutionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2010 20:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/joa-supreme-court-expected-to-rule-soon-on-pcaobs-constitutionality/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court is set to rule soon on a case that could theoretically invalidate the PCAOB and (potentially) all of Sarbanes-Oxley. This month&amp;rsquo;s Journal of Accountancy has an article that does a great job laying out what is at stake.
 Because the Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) does not contain a severability clause, a provision that allows one part of a law to be struck down while keeping the other provisions in force, some observers have pointed out that the entire law could be invalidated by the Supreme Court, which would eliminate the funding of FASB under SOX section 109 and regulations regarding internal control over financial reporting under section 404.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HBR: Does Tax Time Need To Be So Taxing?</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/04/hbr-does-tax-time-need-to-be-so-taxing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 14:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/04/hbr-does-tax-time-need-to-be-so-taxing/</guid>
      <description>The Commissioner of the IRS uses a paid preparer for his tax return…..Really?
 So, I ask again, what’s going on? Here’s one possibility: Over the years, the government turned the tax code over to technical experts, who wrote the regulations, forms, and processes in their own language without regard for the end-user, the citizen, who would be required to use them. As the language and process became more and more arcane, fewer end-users could actually do their own taxes, so an industry of “tax preparers” formed to provide an interface between the tax payer and the taxing authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
