<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Featured on Jared Monger</title>
    <link>https://www.jmonger.com/tags/featured/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Featured on Jared Monger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 17:29:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.jmonger.com/tags/featured/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Should Accountants Be Required to Code</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/should-accountants-be-required-to-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 17:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/should-accountants-be-required-to-code/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, I wonder where I fit on the career spectrum. I am trained as a CPA and 90% of my daily work involves accounting in some form. However, I am also a programmer who geeks out when I find a new way to automate processes or transform data into knowledge. My boss made a comment a few weeks ago in a meeting, “If you want to get Jared excited, ask him about two things: 1) His family or 2) SAS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stanford International Bank Fraud</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/stanford-international-bank-sib-fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 12:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/stanford-international-bank-sib-fraud/</guid>
      <description>While Bernie Madoff was busy having his face shown all over the news last year, a smaller but equally devastating Ponzi scheme was discovered by federal authorities: Standford International Bank (&amp;ldquo;SIB&amp;rdquo;). Because of the dollars involved in Madoff&amp;rsquo;s scam ($65 billion), the Stanford fraud ($7.2 billion) didn&amp;rsquo;t get much press coverage. However, for the victims of this fraud, the outcome may be worse.&#xA;Stanford International Bank was started in 1986 by Allen Stanford.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Managing Well</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/the-art-of-managing-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 17:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/the-art-of-managing-well/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I believe managing is like holding a dove in your hand. If you hold it too tightly you kill it, but if you hold it too loosely, you lose it.&amp;rdquo; -Tommy Lasorda&#xA;There is an art to managing well. I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit I am still learning. As I have been given positions of leadership, one of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to do is look back on leaders I admire for traits to emulate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DO Loops: Part Deux (It&#39;s a pun. Get it?)</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/12/do-loops-part-deux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 18:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/12/do-loops-part-deux/</guid>
      <description>For Part II in this series of posts on DO Loops in SAS, I wanted to discuss an application slightly more complex than the previous example. Loops can not only be used to perform data correction (as shown in the previous post), but can also be very useful in creating new records where none exist. We’ll discuss using order data again as our example. Your client would like you to create a daily trend report showing YTD Quantity Sold by Product by Date.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DO Loops: Useful Tool in SAS User&#39;s Toolbox</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/12/do-loops-a-powerful-tool-in-sas-users-toolbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2009 15:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/12/do-loops-a-powerful-tool-in-sas-users-toolbox/</guid>
      <description>DO Loops in SAS are outside the scope of what most beginning users feel comfortable tackling. However, they are a powerful, time-saving tool in the report writer’s toolbox. For those unfamiliar with programming, loops are a set of instructions that the programmer tells the computer to repeat until predefined condition(s) are true. It’s a simple concept but powerful in execution.&#xA;To illustrate, here is an example of where a loop might be used.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Actuarial Triangle: Powerful Tool for Accounting Estimates</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/11/actuarial-triangle-powerful-tool-for-accounting-estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 19:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/11/actuarial-triangle-powerful-tool-for-accounting-estimates/</guid>
      <description>When individuals outside the profession think of accounting, they don&amp;rsquo;t often consider its subjective nature. Most people assume there are bright line rules and it&amp;rsquo;s the CPA&amp;rsquo;s job to make sure the rules are adhered to. In some instances, there is exact guidance (which makes our lives easier), but in many others CPAs are required to make estimates. Estimates being a nice way of saying, &amp;ldquo;Mr. CPA, please attempt to predict the future.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
