<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Financial Reporting on Jared Monger</title>
    <link>https://www.jmonger.com/tags/financial-reporting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Financial Reporting on Jared Monger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 14:28:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jmonger.com/tags/financial-reporting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bill Gates TED Talk: How State Budgets Are Breaking US Schools</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/bill-gates-ted-talk-how-state-budgets-are-breaking-us-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 14:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/bill-gates-ted-talk-how-state-budgets-are-breaking-us-schools/</guid>
      <description>Bill Gates gave a talk at TED this week that has generated quite a bit of buzz. The video is below. According to Gates, the major issue driving the underfunding of education is state pension obligations. Adding to the mix are governmental accounting standards which allow states to use unrealistic rates of return to discount the liability. Two University of Chicago economists have estimated that if more realistic rates were used the total unfunded pension liability for all US states changes from $310 billion to $2 trillion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FASB/IASB Reaffirm Convergence Timeline</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/fasbiasb-reaffirm-convergence-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 16:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/12/fasbiasb-reaffirm-convergence-timeline/</guid>
      <description>FASB released a report on November 29 with the unwieldy title &amp;ldquo;Progress Report on Commitment to Convergence of Accounting Standards and a Single Set of High Quality Global Accounting Standards&amp;rdquo;. Bottom line, FASB and IASB have reaffirmed their commitment to convergence. High priority projects are on track for a June 2011 completion date. The projects included in that designation are the following.
 Financial instruments Leases Revenue Recognition Consolidations Fair value measurement Derecognition Insurance Contracts  That pretty much covers, well, I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;hellip;80%-90% of everything I&amp;rsquo;ve ever learned about accounting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s a New Sheriff in Town...or Two.</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/07/theres-a-new-sheriff-in-town-or-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2010 13:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/07/theres-a-new-sheriff-in-town-or-two/</guid>
      <description>Last week, the Senate approved some substantial overhauls to the financial regulatory system. The landscape is about to change and CPAs will need to know who the new sheriffs are. As best I can tell, we gained two new agencies and lost one.
The first is the Financial Stability Oversight Council. This is group that will be charged with identifying companies, products or activities that pose a &amp;ldquo;systemic risk&amp;rdquo; to the economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JoA: Supreme Court Expected to Rule Soon on PCAOB&#39;s Constitutionality</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/joa-supreme-court-expected-to-rule-soon-on-pcaobs-constitutionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2010 20:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/06/joa-supreme-court-expected-to-rule-soon-on-pcaobs-constitutionality/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court is set to rule soon on a case that could theoretically invalidate the PCAOB and (potentially) all of Sarbanes-Oxley. This month&amp;rsquo;s Journal of Accountancy has an article that does a great job laying out what is at stake.
 Because the Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) does not contain a severability clause, a provision that allows one part of a law to be struck down while keeping the other provisions in force, some observers have pointed out that the entire law could be invalidated by the Supreme Court, which would eliminate the funding of FASB under SOX section 109 and regulations regarding internal control over financial reporting under section 404.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actuarial Triangle: Powerful Tool for Accounting Estimates</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/11/actuarial-triangle-powerful-tool-for-accounting-estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 19:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/11/actuarial-triangle-powerful-tool-for-accounting-estimates/</guid>
      <description>When individuals outside the profession think of accounting, they don&amp;rsquo;t often consider its subjective nature. Most people assume there are bright line rules and it&amp;rsquo;s the CPA&amp;rsquo;s job to make sure the rules are adhered to. In some instances, there is exact guidance (which makes our lives easier), but in many others CPAs are required to make estimates. Estimates being a nice way of saying, &amp;ldquo;Mr. CPA, please attempt to predict the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Standards Sound Solid</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2008/02/simple-standards-sound-solid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 21:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2008/02/simple-standards-sound-solid/</guid>
      <description>While standard setting in the accounting world is not exactly glamorous, it is, at times, fascinating. This last month the Journal of Accountancy contained an interview with Robert Herz, FASB&amp;rsquo;s current chairman, where he discussed some of the changes coming down the road. The gist of the article was that everything we learned in school will be different (and hopefully simpler) within five to ten years.
Having experienced the headaches of auditing companies that report using both international standards and GAAP, I, for one, am excited about the eventual convergence of standards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If It Looks Like a Duck...</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/12/if-it-looks-like-a-duck/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2007 17:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/12/if-it-looks-like-a-duck/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished a book on the Enron scandal entitled, &amp;ldquo;The Smartest Guys in the Room.&amp;quot; It was a fantastic book and, for the accounting geeks, had good descriptions of the related party transactions that Enron used to prop up their earnings during the late 90s. The SPEs had really fun names like Chewco and Jedi and Whitewing. Inside, I think Fastow must have been a Star Wars fanboy. Amidst all the accounting and structured finance shenanigans, there was a paragraph from an employee that summarized the entire meltdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XBRL = Scrumtrilescent</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/12/xbrl-scrumtrilescent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2007 16:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/12/xbrl-scrumtrilescent/</guid>
      <description>Have I mentioned that I love XBRL? For a numbers guy, the shear beauty of the newly released GAAP taxonomy is so wonderful it invites the creation of a new word&amp;hellip;scrumtrilescent. (Thank you, Will Ferrell).
Seriously, the idea that Company A&amp;rsquo;s financial statements can be downloaded, with all those heady disclosures neatly tagged, and be instantly compared with Company B, makes me want to write a song. What is XBRL you ask?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
