<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fun on Jared Monger</title>
    <link>https://www.jmonger.com/tags/fun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fun on Jared Monger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 21:41:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.jmonger.com/tags/fun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Batman Equation</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/08/the-batman-equation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 21:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/08/the-batman-equation/</guid>
      <description>There is a geometric equation going around the internet that supposedly generates the Batman symbol. Best I can tell, it started at this site, and blew up from there. A user at Stack Exchange took it upon himself to test whether it worked. He mapped out the various functions and looks like it does. Pretty cool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ladies and Gentlemen, My Brother</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/04/ladies-and-gentlemen-my-brother/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2011 22:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/04/ladies-and-gentlemen-my-brother/</guid>
      <description>My younger brother (who also happens to be an accounting major), is finishing up his senior year at University of Tennessee. Apparently, his tax teacher told the class they could use one page of notes on their last test. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what the professor was expecting, but this is what my brother brought. Classic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April Fools Is Better With Visual Basic</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/april-fools-is-better-with-visual-basic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 19:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/april-fools-is-better-with-visual-basic/</guid>
      <description>Happy April Fools-Eve, my fellow practical joke connoisseurs. As someone who enjoys a good laugh at another&amp;rsquo;s expense and also happens to be a bit of a geek, I thought would post the VBA code for two of my favorite Excel-based jokes. For those who aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with Visual Basic for Applications (&amp;ldquo;VBA&amp;rdquo;), it&amp;rsquo;s a programming language that Microsoft created which allows users to customize the functionality of MS Office. For example, I have two macros setup which create hotkeys for Paste Values and Paste Formulas, since I use those on a daily basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Anatomy of an Email Storm</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/the-anatomy-of-an-email-storm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 16:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/the-anatomy-of-an-email-storm/</guid>
      <description>The Wall Street Journal devoted a full article this week to the Reply-All button. Towards the end, they brought up one of Reply-All&amp;rsquo;s unintended consequences: the email storm. This is where someone accidentally emails a very large distribution list, people then Reply-All asking to be removed, then the whole thing explodes until IT gets involved.
I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this happen twice. Both times it unfolded exactly like the chart below. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit, by the time it gets to Phase 4, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to resist the urge to jump into the mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compound Interest: A Lesson From My Dad</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/compound-interest-a-lesson-from-my-dad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 21:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/compound-interest-a-lesson-from-my-dad/</guid>
      <description>“The most powerful force in the universe is compound interest” -Albert Einstein
My dad first taught me about compound interest when I was 18 years old. I was working for him, doing maintenance on our family&amp;rsquo;s office building, and had some extra money burning a hole in my pocket. He wanted to teach me that there are better things to do with money than just blow it on music and video games (a tough argument for a teenager).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Grandfather&#39;s Books</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/my-grandfathers-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 19:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/my-grandfathers-books/</guid>
      <description>Last month, my family and I made a trip to Florida to visit my mom&amp;rsquo;s parents. We had a great visit and while I was there, my grandmother offered to let me have some books from grandfather&amp;rsquo;s study. Grandpa was an engineer turned businessman, and spent his career building things: first automotive parts, then shareholder value.
He had some great accounting textbooks from his MBA at University of Chicago in the 1960&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wired: Cracking the Scratch Lottery Code</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/wired-cracking-the-scratch-lottery-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 14:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/wired-cracking-the-scratch-lottery-code/</guid>
      <description>This was an interesting story from Wired about a Canadian statistician who cracked the Ontario lottery scratch-off algorithm.
 The apparent randomness of the scratch ticket was just a facade, a mathematical lie. And this meant that the lottery system might actually be solvable, just like those mining samples. “At the time, I had no intention of cracking the tickets,” he says. He was just curious about the algorithm that produced the numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Lords of Finance, The Bankers Who Broke the World</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/01/book-review-lords-of-finance-the-bankers-who-broke-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 18:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/01/book-review-lords-of-finance-the-bankers-who-broke-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Recently finished a book on the Great Depression called Lords of Finance: The Bankers Who Broke the World. It was a 500+ page behemoth, but a surprisingly quick read. The story focuses on four central bankers during the 20s and 30s: Benjamin Strong of the Federal Reserve of New York, Montagu Norman of the Bank of England, Emile Morceau of the Banque de France, and Hjalmer Schacht of the Reichsbank of Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HBR: On Creative Accounting, Two Creativity Myths</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/hbr-on-creative-accounting-two-creativity-myths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 14:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/hbr-on-creative-accounting-two-creativity-myths/</guid>
      <description>Harvard Business Review had a good blog post this morning called On Creative Accounting: Two Creativity Myths. The term &amp;ldquo;creative accounting&amp;rdquo; conjures up images of Enron, and other massive financial reporting frauds. However, the author points out that creativity, itself, is morally neutral, and because creativity in accounting can be bad, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that it must be bad. Also, I liked the cartoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xkcd: SQL Injection Comic</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/xkcd-sql-injection-comic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 13:54:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/xkcd-sql-injection-comic/</guid>
      <description>I love xkcd. This is old, but I&amp;rsquo;m slow on the uptake. I also love that a comic spawned a website on how to prevent SQL injection attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Genealogy, Chance, and God</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/thoughts-on-genealogy-chance-and-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 22:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/thoughts-on-genealogy-chance-and-god/</guid>
      <description>Prelude: This post doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much particularly to do with numbers or accounting, but it does have a lot to do with me. There are some thoughts on probability as well.
Those who follow me on Twitter may have noticed, I have developed a recent fascination with genealogy. It started a few weeks ago during a conversation with my wife where I mentioned it might be nice to pass on a family tree to my son.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benford&#39;s Law</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/benfords-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 01:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/benfords-law/</guid>
      <description>My wife tells me my blog is boring because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have enough pictures&amp;hellip;and also it&amp;rsquo;s about accounting. So, with that in mind, I am prepared to blow your mind with this post, pictures and all. Benford&amp;rsquo;s Law. Who&amp;rsquo;s heard of it? Anybody. Anybody. Bueller&amp;hellip;. This is Benford&amp;rsquo;s Law.
What, equations don&amp;rsquo;t do it for you? Well then, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in. Benford&amp;rsquo;s Law is one of those things that can be proven mathematically, but flies in the face of common sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darth JEDAR</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/darth-jedar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 23:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/darth-jedar/</guid>
      <description>I found this picture in a pile of papers under my stairs and it reminded me of a fun memory so I thought I would share. While working at D&amp;amp;T, I was stationed for the better part of a year on one large client. During that period, I spent more time with those people than I did with my wife. We got to know each other well, and as would be expected with long hours and tough deadlines, some nicknames emerged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Light Reading</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/some-light-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 15:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/some-light-reading/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick rundown of the blogs that have recently inspired my work. I digest a huge number of RSS feeds each week, and it takes a good headline for me to open (and read) a post. These blogs consistently deliver.
 Seth&amp;rsquo;s Blog - Seth Godin really doesn&amp;rsquo;t need an introduction. At least not from me. He is a king of metaphor and I find his blog to be inspired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Loopholes</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/game-loopholes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 13:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/game-loopholes/</guid>
      <description>Most of my daily life involves using numbers at work. However, numbers also have a significant role in my play. As a kid, I was a baseball card collector: bought them, traded them, memorized them. I think I liked baseball cards not for the personalities they represented, but because of the data on the back. All games involve numbers. Games of chance, games of skill: it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter. Numbers are the way we measure performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nowadays, Everyone Is a Geek</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/nowadays-everyone-is-a-geek/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 16:15:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/08/nowadays-everyone-is-a-geek/</guid>
      <description>These days everyone is calling themselves a geek. Somewhere along the way, it became a fashionable term. With the rise of the mobile web and modern day social networking, everyone, it seems, is into technology. Welcome newcomers. It was not always so. Geeks have been around looooong before it was fashionable. In fact, I was a geek before the average man even knew what the internet was. The world wide web was only used by institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Five Android Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/07/top-five-android-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2010 03:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/07/top-five-android-apps/</guid>
      <description>This is normally an accounting blog, but, (as I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;ve figured out) I am also a bit of a tech geek. Recently, I got my first real smartphone, a Motorola Droid. The Droid has been a game changer for me and I really can&amp;rsquo;t imagine where this technology will be in another 5-10 years. That said, I thought I would throw my two cents in regarding my top five favorite apps I have come across so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keynes vs. Hayek Rap Video</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/07/keynes-vs-hayek-rap-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2010 12:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/07/keynes-vs-hayek-rap-video/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit, sometimes the content on this site can be a little dry. I came across a video this week I thought might add a little humor. Anyone who takes Econ 101 hears about John Maynard Keynes, Milton Friedman, and F.A. Hayek. Ususally, our introduction to these individuals is in the form of a documentary film of some sort, complete with a British narrator, Ken Burns Effect photo zooming, and a long enough run time to complete a short nap.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>