<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fun on Jared Monger</title>
    <link>https://www.jmonger.com/tags/fun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fun on Jared Monger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 19:49:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jmonger.com/tags/fun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>April Fools Is Better With Visual Basic</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/april-fools-is-better-with-visual-basic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 19:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/april-fools-is-better-with-visual-basic/</guid>
      <description>Happy April Fools-Eve, my fellow practical joke connoisseurs. As someone who enjoys a good laugh at another&amp;rsquo;s expense and also happens to be a bit of a geek, I thought would post the VBA code for two of my favorite Excel-based jokes. For those who aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with Visual Basic for Applications (&amp;ldquo;VBA&amp;rdquo;), it&amp;rsquo;s a programming language that Microsoft created which allows users to customize the functionality of MS Office. For example, I have two macros setup which create hotkeys for Paste Values and Paste Formulas, since I use those on a daily basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Grandfather&#39;s Books</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/my-grandfathers-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 19:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/my-grandfathers-books/</guid>
      <description>Last month, my family and I made a trip to Florida to visit my mom&amp;rsquo;s parents. We had a great visit and while I was there, my grandmother offered to let me have some books from grandfather&amp;rsquo;s study. Grandpa was an engineer turned businessman, and spent his career building things: first automotive parts, then shareholder value.
He had some great accounting textbooks from his MBA at University of Chicago in the 1960&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
