<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SAS on Jared Monger</title>
    <link>https://www.jmonger.com/tags/sas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SAS on Jared Monger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 15:55:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jmonger.com/tags/sas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SAS EG: Filtering a Dataset via Prompt Manager Variable</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/sas-eg-filtering-a-dataset-via-prompt-manager-variable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 15:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/sas-eg-filtering-a-dataset-via-prompt-manager-variable/</guid>
      <description>Nobody who reads this blog is likely a SAS programmer. However, on the off chance this would be useful to someone who finds it via Google, I wanted to post. Currently, I am working on a project in SAS Enterprise Guide where I needed to allow the user to provide variable value(s) via prompt manager and then filter the resulting dataset based on the user&amp;rsquo;s input. After rubbing a few brain cells together, created a macro that does the trick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actuarial Triangle: Powerful Tool for Accounting Estimates</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/11/actuarial-triangle-powerful-tool-for-accounting-estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 19:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/11/actuarial-triangle-powerful-tool-for-accounting-estimates/</guid>
      <description>When individuals outside the profession think of accounting, they don&amp;rsquo;t often consider its subjective nature. Most people assume there are bright line rules and it&amp;rsquo;s the CPA&amp;rsquo;s job to make sure the rules are adhered to. In some instances, there is exact guidance (which makes our lives easier), but in many others CPAs are required to make estimates. Estimates being a nice way of saying, &amp;ldquo;Mr. CPA, please attempt to predict the future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
