<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fraud on Jared Monger</title>
    <link>https://www.jmonger.com/tags/fraud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fraud on Jared Monger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 19:57:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.jmonger.com/tags/fraud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stanford International Bank Fraud Conviction: 110 Year Prison Sentence</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/09/stanford-international-bank-fraud-conviction-110-year-prison-sentence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 19:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/09/stanford-international-bank-fraud-conviction-110-year-prison-sentence/</guid>
      <description>Two years ago, I wrote a long post about the Stanford International Bank Fraud.&#xA;I recently thought about the story and realized I never followed up to see what happened. After a quick Google search, I was pleased to see that Allen Stanford was convicted and sentenced to 110 years in prison.&#xA;The most amazing part is even after his conviction Stanford still claims he wasn&amp;rsquo;t running a Ponzi scheme and the government is responsible for his victims&amp;rsquo; losses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sino-Forest, Short Sellers Allege Ponzi Scheme</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/06/sino-forest-short-sellers-allege-ponzi-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 18:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/06/sino-forest-short-sellers-allege-ponzi-scheme/</guid>
      <description>There is an interesting alleged accounting fraud unfolding in China. Sino-Forest Corporation, a Chinese company in the business of selling timber, has been accused by short sellers of being a massive Ponzi scheme. Like Enron, they seem to be running their business through a complex system of subsidiaries in order to obfuscate transactions. One of the funnier quotes from the short sellers&amp;rsquo; report is below:&#xA;Despite TRE’s opacity on the revenue side, we have overwhelming evidence that the $231.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benford&#39;s Law</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/benfords-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 01:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/benfords-law/</guid>
      <description>My wife tells me my blog is boring because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have enough pictures&amp;hellip;and also it&amp;rsquo;s about accounting. So, with that in mind, I am prepared to blow your mind with this post, pictures and all. Benford&amp;rsquo;s Law. Who&amp;rsquo;s heard of it? Anybody. Anybody. Bueller&amp;hellip;. This is Benford&amp;rsquo;s Law.&#xA;What, equations don&amp;rsquo;t do it for you? Well then, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in. Benford&amp;rsquo;s Law is one of those things that can be proven mathematically, but flies in the face of common sense.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stanford International Bank Fraud</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/stanford-international-bank-sib-fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 12:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/10/stanford-international-bank-sib-fraud/</guid>
      <description>While Bernie Madoff was busy having his face shown all over the news last year, a smaller but equally devastating Ponzi scheme was discovered by federal authorities: Standford International Bank (&amp;ldquo;SIB&amp;rdquo;). Because of the dollars involved in Madoff&amp;rsquo;s scam ($65 billion), the Stanford fraud ($7.2 billion) didn&amp;rsquo;t get much press coverage. However, for the victims of this fraud, the outcome may be worse.&#xA;Stanford International Bank was started in 1986 by Allen Stanford.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If It Looks Like a Duck...</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/12/if-it-looks-like-a-duck/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2007 17:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2007/12/if-it-looks-like-a-duck/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished a book on the Enron scandal entitled, &amp;ldquo;The Smartest Guys in the Room.&amp;rdquo; It was a fantastic book and, for the accounting geeks, had good descriptions of the related party transactions that Enron used to prop up their earnings during the late 90s. The SPEs had really fun names like Chewco and Jedi and Whitewing. Inside, I think Fastow must have been a Star Wars fanboy. Amidst all the accounting and structured finance shenanigans, there was a paragraph from an employee that summarized the entire meltdown.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
