<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jared Monger</title>
    <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jared Monger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 09:05:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jmonger.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Installing Arch Linux in VMware Workstation Player</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2020/09/installing-arch-linux-in-vmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 09:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2020/09/installing-arch-linux-in-vmware/</guid>
      <description>During this time when we are all isolated in our homes because of COVID-19, I have tried to make the most of it and learn some new skills. Something I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to get better at is Linux. I learn best by diving into the deep end of the pool, so I decided to install Arch Linux in VMware Workstation Player as a learning experience. This blog post is to document the process for future reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel Pull Function</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/02/excel-pull-function-creating-dynamic-links-to-closed-workbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 21:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2012/02/excel-pull-function-creating-dynamic-links-to-closed-workbooks/</guid>
      <description>I was working on a project this week that required aggregation of data from many, many different Excel workbooks (and various tabs within those workbooks) into one unified dashboard. Now, this can be accomplished with traditional linking, but anyone who has tried to link more than a few workbooks together will tell you this is a pain to maintain and often not very reliable.
One useful function for creating dynamic links within the same workbook is INDIRECT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April Fools Is Better With Visual Basic</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/april-fools-is-better-with-visual-basic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 19:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/03/april-fools-is-better-with-visual-basic/</guid>
      <description>Happy April Fools-Eve, my fellow practical joke connoisseurs. As someone who enjoys a good laugh at another&amp;rsquo;s expense and also happens to be a bit of a geek, I thought would post the VBA code for two of my favorite Excel-based jokes. For those who aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with Visual Basic for Applications (&amp;ldquo;VBA&amp;rdquo;), it&amp;rsquo;s a programming language that Microsoft created which allows users to customize the functionality of MS Office. For example, I have two macros setup which create hotkeys for Paste Values and Paste Formulas, since I use those on a daily basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Grandfather&#39;s Books</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/my-grandfathers-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 19:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2011/02/my-grandfathers-books/</guid>
      <description>Last month, my family and I made a trip to Florida to visit my mom&amp;rsquo;s parents. We had a great visit and while I was there, my grandmother offered to let me have some books from grandfather&amp;rsquo;s study. Grandpa was an engineer turned businessman, and spent his career building things: first automotive parts, then shareholder value.
He had some great accounting textbooks from his MBA at University of Chicago in the 1960&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAS EG: Filtering a Dataset via Prompt Manager Variable</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/sas-eg-filtering-a-dataset-via-prompt-manager-variable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 15:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2010/11/sas-eg-filtering-a-dataset-via-prompt-manager-variable/</guid>
      <description>Nobody who reads this blog is likely a SAS programmer. However, on the off chance this would be useful to someone who finds it via Google, I wanted to post. Currently, I am working on a project in SAS Enterprise Guide where I needed to allow the user to provide variable value(s) via prompt manager and then filter the resulting dataset based on the user&amp;rsquo;s input. After rubbing a few brain cells together, created a macro that does the trick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actuarial Triangle: Powerful Tool for Accounting Estimates</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/11/actuarial-triangle-powerful-tool-for-accounting-estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 19:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/11/actuarial-triangle-powerful-tool-for-accounting-estimates/</guid>
      <description>When individuals outside the profession think of accounting, they don&amp;rsquo;t often consider its subjective nature. Most people assume there are bright line rules and it&amp;rsquo;s the CPA&amp;rsquo;s job to make sure the rules are adhered to. In some instances, there is exact guidance (which makes our lives easier), but in many others CPAs are required to make estimates. Estimates being a nice way of saying, &amp;ldquo;Mr. CPA, please attempt to predict the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel Protect Sheet Hack</title>
      <link>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/02/excel-protect-sheet-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 15:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jmonger.com/posts/2009/02/excel-protect-sheet-hack/</guid>
      <description>I had a situation yesterday where I was trying to get into a password protected Excel sheet and did not know the password. After a quick Google search I realized that the &amp;ldquo;Protect Sheet&amp;rdquo; function in Excel has a backdoor which can be exploited with a few lines of VBA. I didn&amp;rsquo;t write the code below, but I am not ashamed to use it.
The algorithm relies on a backdoor password that can be 1 to 9 characters long where each character is either an &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; except the last which can be any character from ASCII code 32 to 255.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
